<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://akua.co/blogs/the-new-wave.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://akua.co/blogs/the-new-wave"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://akua.co/blogs/the-new-wave.atom"/>
  <title>AKUA - The New Wave</title>
  <updated>2019-06-10T15:13:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AKUA</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akua.co/blogs/the-new-wave/world-oceans-week-recap</id>
    <published>2019-06-10T15:13:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-06-10T15:26:47-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://akua.co/blogs/the-new-wave/world-oceans-week-recap"/>
    <title>World Ocean&apos;s Week Recap</title>
    <author>
      <name>Courtney Boyd</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">This week, we had the pleasure of participating in World Ocean's Week in New York City. From speaking at Explorer’s Club to sharing our Kelp Jerky with explorers and scientists from around the world to bringing Kelp Jerky aboard the UN’s party on the Peace Boat, it was high vibes all the way through!</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://akua.co/blogs/the-new-wave/world-oceans-week-recap">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">This week, we had the pleasure of participating in World Ocean's Week in New York City.</h2>
From speaking at Explorer’s Club to sharing our Kelp Jerky with explorers and scientists from around the world to bringing Kelp Jerky aboard the UN’s party on the Peace Boat, it was high vibes all the way through!<br><br>As World Ocean’s Week comes to an end, we’d love to share a few things we learned with you.<br><br>
<h3>1) Our seas are drowning in plastic pollution</h3>
Every year, 8 million metric tons of plastics enter the seas, adding to the estimated 150 million metric tons already circulating there. The organization notes on its website, “That’s like dumping one New York City garbage truck full of plastic into the ocean every minute of every day for an entire year.” - The US nonprofit Ocean Conservancy<br> <br>
<h3>2) Straws made out of seaweed are coming</h3>
San Francisco startup Loliware is launching biodegradable straws this summer made out of sustainably sourced ocean-farmed kelp!<br><br>
<h3>3) Sushi made from plants tastes just as delicious</h3>
Ocean Hugger Foods makes sustainable, plant-based alternatives to popular seafood proteins. For example, their product Ahimi is the world's first plant-based alternative to raw tuna, made from tomatoes. <br><br>
<h3>4) Scientists have discovered how to make coral grow 40x faster</h3>
<p>It typically takes coral 25 to 75 years to reach sexual maturity but David Vaughan at the Mote Laboratory is growing coral 40 times faster than in the wild with a new coral fragmentation method. Vaughn plans to "plant" 100,000 pieces of coral around the Florida Reef Tract by 2019 and millions more around the world in the years to come.<br><br></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0012/6425/5042/files/Screen_Shot_2019-06-10_at_1.28.17_PM_large.png?v=1560187719" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>5) Ocean pollution has a greater effect on women</h3>
“The effects of pollution and climate change on the oceans have a disproportionate impact on women. This year, we strive to build a greater ocean and gender literacy, and to discover possible ways to promote gender equality in ocean-related activities such as marine scientific research, fisheries, labour at sea as well as policy-making and management.” <br><br>- The United Nations<br><br>
<h3>6) Scientists have proven health benefits of being by water</h3>
<p>Living by coasts leads to an improved sense of physical health and well-being and contact with water induces a meditative state that makes us happier, healthier, calmer, more creative, and more capable of awe. At team AKUA, we just call this "living the brand".</p>
<h3></h3>
<h3>Have you entered our epic Ocean's Week Giveaway?</h3>
<p>From swimsuits made out of recycled fish nets to ocean-loving bath and beauty care, we've teamed up with five amazing beach-loving brands to gift you $500+ in goodies for your summer holidays. And tomorrow is the last day to win so enter <a href="https://www.dojomojo.com/promo-lookup/b8d2aa1b-2077-490f-94f5-881b1aba360a?utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=Celebrate%20World%20Ocean's%20Day%20with%20these%20Five%20Beach%20Worthy%20Brands&amp;utm_term=World%20Ocean's%20Day&amp;utm_content=Giveaway">here!</a></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0012/6425/5042/files/Canva_-_People_in_Ocean_large.jpg?v=1559995682" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akua.co/blogs/the-new-wave/ocean-facts-for-the-wave-hearted</id>
    <published>2019-06-08T08:25:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-06-08T09:28:21-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://akua.co/blogs/the-new-wave/ocean-facts-for-the-wave-hearted"/>
    <title>Ocean Facts for the Wave-hearted</title>
    <author>
      <name>Eve Palmer</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[It's officially World Ocean's Day! While every day is like World Ocean’s Day at AKUA, it’s great to have a global day to celebrate with one another. After all, our oceans support our very existence, and are home to most of the living beings walking (and swimming) on Earth. Here are 10 facts to blow you out of the water (or are, at the very least, sea-riously interesting) :<p><a class="read-more" href="https://akua.co/blogs/the-new-wave/ocean-facts-for-the-wave-hearted">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">It’s officially World Ocean’s Day! While every day is like World Ocean’s Day at AKUA, it’s great to have a global day to celebrate with one another. After all, our oceans support our very existence, and are home to most of the living beings walking (and swimming) on Earth. </p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Here are 10 facts to blow you out of the water (or are, at the very least, sea-riously interesting) :</p>
<h3>1) The largest mountain range on Earth is actually underwater.</h3>
<p>The <a href="https://www.britannica.com/place/Mid-Atlantic-Ridge">Mid-Atlantic Ridge</a> is 10,000 miles long and 1,000 miles wide. While most of it lies underwater, some areas poke above sea-level, forming various islands along the way.</p>
<h3>2) Over 70% of the oxygen we breathe comes from the ocean.</h3>
<p>While the rainforests contribute a fair amount of oxygen to the world (<a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.org/activity/save-the-plankton-breathe-freely/">28%</a>), marine plants (such as kelp) produce the other two-thirds for our planet through photosynthesis. This means that they take in CO2 from the air and convert it to oxygen for us to breathe!</p>
<h3>3) Rivers and lakes can exist underwater as well!</h3>
<p>Yes, you read that correctly! Different densities in the water form a separation of flows in the ocean, allowing for <a href="http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20170706-the-mystery-of-the-massive-deep-sea-rivers">rivers to cut through</a> the large bodies of water and flow at different speeds. These rivers go on to carve valleys into the ocean floor which make them appear like above-water ones with banks on either side.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0012/6425/5042/files/Canva_-_Gray_and_Silver_School_of_Fish_Underwater_Photography_large.jpg?v=1559995788" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="498" height="248"></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>4) 80% of the pollution that exists in our oceans is due to land-based ventures.</h3>
<p>Our oceans are <a href="https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/pollution.html">constantly at the peril</a> from the downstream (literally) effects of businesses on land. From greenhouse gas emissions to factory farming, our oceans are suffering because of the actions of large companies going unregulated. This includes pollutants like fertilizer runoff and pesticides used by the agriculture industry as well as fossil fuels from the air that settle into the water.</p>
<h3>5) If all of our glaciers and ice sheets melt, most major cities in the world will be submerged.</h3>
<p>As our <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/global-warming/big-thaw/">ice sheets melt</a>, it’s important to consider what this means in regards to our wellbeing. It’s no joke that the average temperature on earth is only getting warmer, meaning that soon our oceans could be 262 feet taller within the next century - enough to cover most of our cities in water.</p>
<h3>6) 90% of the volcanic activity that takes place on our Earth happens in the oceans.</h3>
<p>There exists a large number of active <a href="https://oceanexplorer.noaa.gov/facts/volcanoes.html">volcanoes on the ocean floor</a>. One area in particular is located in the South Pacific and is said to hold a handful of volcanoes that are ready to erupt any day now! These underwater eruptions are why we have many of the small islands that are floating our waters today.</p>
<h3>7) Our deepest trench on Earth is hidden far below the water.</h3>
<p>Not only does the ocean contain our largest mountain range on Earth, it also sinks to the deepest point of the planet. Located in the Mariana Trench, the <a href="https://allthatsinteresting.com/challenger-deep-deepest-part-of-the-ocean">Challenger Deep</a> is an additional trench within Mariana diving a whopping 36,000 feet below the ocean’s surface. This means that it’s the deepest part of the entire world - taller than Mt. Everest!</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0012/6425/5042/files/Canva_-_Yacht_In_Body_Of_Water_large.jpg?v=1559995857" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>8) The width of the Pacific Ocean is greater than the moon.</h3>
<p>The Pacific Ocean is <a href="https://bestlifeonline.com/crazy-ocean-facts/">12,300 miles wide</a> at its largest point. This expanse travels all the way from Indonesia to Colombia. The diameter of the moon is 2,158.8 miles wide, which means that the width of the Pacific Ocean is actually around five times the width of the moon.</p>
<h3>9) 50% of the ocean is unprotected by global governments.</h3>
<p>Half of the ocean is labeled as <a href="http://savethesea.org/STS%20ocean_facts.htm">“The High Seas”</a> which means that those areas are fair game to unsafe and <a href="https://crimereads.com/crime-on-the-high-seas/">harmful practices</a>. This means that things like pirate looting or exploitative fishing practices (such as overfishing or targeting endangered species) go completely unmonitored.</p>
<h3>10) One drop of water takes 1000 years to travel around the entire globe.</h3>
<p>Believe it or not, water can actually travel <a href="https://science.howstuffworks.com/environmental/earth/oceanography/ocean-current3.htm">across the entire Earth</a>. Through different temperatures and pressures spanning the waters, a single drop is able to make its way around by turning into ice at some points and also changing its density based on salt levels and environmental changes. <br><br></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0012/6425/5042/files/Canva_-_White_Plant_large.jpg?v=1559995932" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p><br>Our world’s oceans are incredible forces spanning across the Earth. It’s important to be educated in the ways our governments and corporations are exploiting them at the expense of our present and future. <br><br>So how can you kelp… I mean help? We’ve got you! By cutting down your <a href="http://www.greeneducationfoundation.org/nationalgreenweeksub/waste-reduction-tips/tips-to-use-less-plastic.html">plastic use</a> (carry around reusable bags, buy bulk items from markets instead of packaged ones, bring your own to-go containers to restaurants), <a href="https://www.forksoverknives.com/plant-based-primer-beginners-guide-starting-plant-based-diet/#gs.hi4lqf">eating plant-based</a> or <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2017/03/15/520023117/i-want-to-eat-fish-responsibly-but-the-seafood-guides-are-so-confusing">sustainable catch</a>, and paying attention to reducing your carbon footprint in even the smallest of ways throughout your day (like <a href="http://www.sodgod.com/composting/">composting</a> or <a href="http://affinitymagazine.us/2017/02/23/why-thrift-shopping-benefits-you-and-our-planet/">not buying fast fashion</a>). </p>
<p><br>Happy World Ocean’s Day! Enter our epic giveaway <a href="http://bit.ly/oceanfun">HERE</a>. :)<br><br></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Follow us!<br>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/LifeAkua">@lifeakua</a> • Instagram: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/lifeakua/">@lifeakua</a> • Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/LifeAkua/?eid=ARA_gwDvNzllYcLEvGvP0NXvv8do6VV8Oz5aw4e1roI0k5YQwOmRY678CFaCCqOFcathe6WaWEYe9ANh">AKUA</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akua.co/blogs/the-new-wave/kelpforyourhealth</id>
    <published>2019-06-03T09:42:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-06-17T13:26:10-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://akua.co/blogs/the-new-wave/kelpforyourhealth"/>
    <title>Kelp For Your Health!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Eve Palmer</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>Seaweed, and kelp specifically, is a vital superfood that many people in the West have ignored for decades. While the health benefits of this virtuous sea vegetable are vast, here are five reasons you need to know why kelp is the new kale.</span></p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://akua.co/blogs/the-new-wave/kelpforyourhealth">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2 class="p1"><span class="s1"></span></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Have you heard “kelp is the new kale”?</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let us tell you why! Seaweed, and kelp specifically, is a vital superfood that many people in the West have ignored for decades. While the health benefits of this virtuous sea vegetable are vast, here are five reasons you need to know why kelp is the new kale:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Rich Source of Iodine </strong></li>
</ul>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;">Naturally occurring in kelp, iodine is important for balancing the thyroid system and ensuring the metabolism is working at its top functionality. Iodine is also <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://draxe.com/kelp/">said to maintain</a></span> healthy brain activity as well as help with brain development in children.</div>
<ul>
<li><strong>Weight Loss</strong></li>
</ul>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;">Kelp is one of the only foods that actually expands in your stomach! So, it leaves you feeling full and satisfied for longer. This, along with the metabolic boost mentioned above, is why kelp is often recommended to aid weight loss.</div>
<ul>
<li><strong>Anti-Inflammatory</strong></li>
</ul>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;">
<span>Kelp contains </span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://drjockers.com/6-major-health-benefits-sea-kelp/">Fucoidan</a></span><span><span>, a polysaccharide which is known to be an anti-inflammatory. Additionally, scientists have linked it </span></span>to reducing cholesterol levels in the bloodstream.</div>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>Improved Bone Density</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span>
</li>
</ul>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;">
<span>Kelp is a great source of </span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.mindbodygreen.com/articles/kelp-the-health-benefits-and-supplements">Vitamin K</a></span><span>. This is a key vitamin for supporting bone density and important in helping to prevent issues like osteoporosis or arthritis.</span>
</div>
<ul>
<li><strong>Everything Vegans Need!</strong></li>
</ul>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;">
<span>We say this because kelp is rich in B vitamins as well as iron. B12 is a vitamin that’s not commonly available in vegan snack products unless they’re fortified. If a person has low </span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.healthline.com/nutrition/vitamin-b12-benefits#section2">B12 levels</a></span><span>, they may feel fatigued and experience brain fog. Effects of iron deficiency are similar. It’s very important to monitor these levels in order to feel like your best self!</span>
</div>
<p>As you can sea, kelp is truly the superfood of the sea! Kelp is also very healthy for the environment. It cleans CO2 out of the water and produces more oxygen for us to breathe! There’s an increasing number of delicious seaweed products on the market - <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://akua.co/collections/kelp-jerky">Kelp Jerky</a></span> being one of them!</p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0012/6425/5042/files/Image_from_iOS-27_large.jpg?v=1559569075" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Follow us!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/LifeAkua">@lifeakua</a> <span>• </span>Instagram: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/lifeakua/">@lifeakua</a> <span>•</span> Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/LifeAkua/?eid=ARA_gwDvNzllYcLEvGvP0NXvv8do6VV8Oz5aw4e1roI0k5YQwOmRY678CFaCCqOFcathe6WaWEYe9ANh">AKUA</a></p>
</blockquote>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
